CURRICULUM VITAE

Mr (Dr.) Priyank V. Shah

306, Sandstone Appartment, Behind TV-9 News Channel Centre, Jivraj Park, Ahmedabad-380051,

Gujarat, India.

Mob: - 08460406242

Email address: priyankvshah@hotmail.com

Profile:

I am Doctor with more than 10 years' experience in medical and healthcare sector having positive, determined and reliable attitude. I am also Self-motivated with successful record in achieving targets. Love a challenging task. I am a good communicator with interpersonal skills at all levels and should be an asset to a business. Possessing excellent people skill with good communication. To build trust and inspire teamwork, facilitate and support team decisions and expand team capabilities is my motto.

Educational Qualifications:

I believe in preparing myself with relevant knowledge; upgrading my working capacity.

- 2011 MBA in Healthcare Management from *University of Wales, London, U.K.* (Accounts, Finance, Healthcare, Managing markets, Managing people, Information Technology). *Dissertation title: Discharge planning for elderly at Watford general hospital, UK under Hertfordshire county council, London, U.K.*
- 2008 B.H.M.S (Bachelors in Homoeopathy Medicine and Surgery) from *Bharati Vidyapeeth University*, *Pune*, *India*.
- 2008 C.G.O. (Certificate course in Gynaecology & Obstetrics) from *Bombay Institute of Medical Technology, Pune, India.*
- 2008 C.C.H. (Certificate course in Child Health and Nutrition) from *Bombay Institute of Medical Technology*, *Pune*, *India*.
- 2002 H.S.C. from C.B.S.E. Board, India from Coast Guard Public School, Daman, India.
- 1999 S.S.C. from I.C.S.E. Board, India from AtulVidyalaya, Atul, India.

Skills:

- "BEST HOSPITAL ADMINISTRATOR AWARD 2013, 2014" consistently by Adarsh Multi-speciality Hospital Ltd., Valsad, Gujarat
- "BEST CENTRE MANAGER AWARD 2016, 2017 & 2018" PROGRESSIVELY FOR Gujarat region by Centre for Sight (Group of Eye Hospitals).
- NABH & QCI Co-ordinator Preparation of reports NABH accreditation from inception to successful Accreditation of Hospital. Also streamlined functioning of clinical and non-clinical departments in Hospital by developing policies & procedures and supervising implementation of the same.
- Advanced knowledge of assessment, planning, implementation, personnel procedures and evaluation of public health programs.
- Knowledge of Medical services funding, grant writing, and budget monitoring.
- Advanced leadership, group process, group facilitation and negotiation skills.
- Knowledge regarding Microsoft PowerPoint, Word, Excel and Conversant with operating systems of Microsoft Windows 95/98/ME/2000/XP.
- Computer Literate (Microsoft Office Products).
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills.

- Ability to abide by company policies and also maintaining attendance to support required quality and quantity of work.
- Having qualities like conducting seminars and presentations to alert the community about certain serious diseases in the related field.

Employment History:

December 2018 to Present, CHIEF OPERATIONS OFFICER (COO) at Innovative Healing Systems (India) Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad.

Responsibilities:-

- Developing and integrating staffing programs designed to attract the highest calibre of talent while satisfying the needs of clients.
- Collaborate with our CEO for corporate growth and evolution.
- Assist the CFO with financial projections and analyses of existing programs and policies.
- Manage service employees and train them in the latest leadership and technical skills so they can better serve our clients.
- Helming budgeting and resource allocation efforts alongside the other C-level executives and the senior management team.
- Ensuring all program initiatives align with the company's core values and culture.
- Providing leadership to those under my command so that other staff might take more initiative in their roles.
- Measuring effectiveness and efficiency of operational processes both internally and externally and finds ways to improve processes.
- Developing and implementing growth strategies.
- Raising capital through banks or outside investors to help foster growth or obtain sales goals.
- Motivating staff to meet or surpass organisational and sales goals with Chief Business Developer.
- Oversees daily operations and makes adjustments as necessary
- Presenting new ideas and cash flow strategies to board of directors and other company officers
- Evaluating newly implemented sales plans
- Providing a system for employee salaries and benefits, and makes sure employees feel valued
- Promoting communication between colleagues for the benefit of information flow and to curb any problems that arise.

April 2016 – November 2018, CENTRE MANAGER at Centre for Sight, Ahmedabad. Responsibilities:-

- Prepare the annual budget with the assistance of Corporate team
- Monitor the performance of the Center in terms of revenue & profitability against targets and take corrective steps as required
- Monitor the budget utilization and other financial measures for the center; Study and analyse causes for significant deviation from budget and take corrective action for the same, if required
- Oversee if the right number and quality of manpower is hired in accordance with the manpower planning
- Establish corporate culture by having daily de-briefing by respective department SPOC (reportees)
- Support HR in investigating and resolving critical attrition and increasing employee engagement levels at the center
- Prepare performance standards for the center with strategic plans of the organization.
- Conduct regular analysis in centre, identify trends and collaborate with the Corporate Medical & Quality team to ensure appropriate action plans operationally.
- Devise and implement action plans for achievement of financial targets of the center
- Build new business relationships with doctors/facilitators etc., thus contributing to increase in the revenues of the center

- Assist and coordinate with the center level sales team in establishing CFS brand in the locality/area/city through various sales (BTL) and marketing campaigns (ATL)
- Ensure implementation & supervision of business lead capturing & conversions
- Focus on continuously enhancing Patient's experience through interactions and involvement to determine expectations
- Prepare and maintain effective scheduling and availability of resources to ensure on time surgeries and ensure efficient procedures in billing are being followed
- Ensure timely, accurate and legible documentation is maintained by clinical & non clinical team
- Ensure pre & post-surgical nursing care is of highest quality by continuous assistance, training and monitoring
- Ensure that ethical medical practice is followed at all times at the center
- Coordinate with the medical directors and ensure that all clinical policies and procedures within the Center meets the requirements of State/Local rules & regulations and other licensing or accrediting bodies
- Ensure maintenance of highest standards of hygiene and cleanliness in order to achieve least number of hospital acquired infections
- Ensure compliance on Statutory Guidelines in consultation with corporate team
- Interact with patients and attendants and build lasting relationships
- Maintain an efficient patient feedback and response system to gather feedback and respond to problems in a timely manner and ensure resolution
- Undertake cost optimization initiatives such as reducing the usage of consumables, monitoring Fixed costs, variable costs, overheads etc.
- Oversee safekeeping of center medical records and ensure availability at all times for auditing & reference purposes (implement easy retrieval mechanism)
- Act as an escalation point for all operational issues related to the facility and take suitable action by interfacing with the concerned stakeholders
- Oversee duty rosters in order to ensure effective utilization of manpower and managing of outsourced staff and ensure efficient running of the center
- Act as pivotal point for all Corporate communication & ensure timely response
- In addition to above mentioned duties & responsibilities, any addition or change will be communicated by Immediate Supervisor/ Medical Director/ Respective HOD.

April 2015 – March 2016, EHR/EMR Product Manager at Integrated Systems Management, Ahmedabad.

Responsibilities:-

- Defining EHR strategy and multi-year product roadmaps with clear objectives and long-term vision, with particular focus on new EHR opportunities and innovation, and expansion and additional penetration of existing EHR.
- Translating strategies into actionable requirements for product development. Initiate and analyse
 market research to understand customer behaviour, product satisfaction, changes in documentation
 and reporting requirements and trends, and emerging service opportunities for EHR. Establish clear
 release objectives based on this information. Regularly review metrics and measures to support
 closed-loop feedback process which ensures customer satisfaction, competitive advantage, and lowcost enrolment, delivery, and support.
- Identifying product enhancements that balance a favourable return on investment with customer needs. Assess/determine buy, build, partner decisions, and serve as senior sponsor to all business partnerships leveraged within the EHR product(s).
- Work with development scrum teams on a regular basis to ensure service releases are delivered on scope, on time, and on quality. Collaborate with other departments to ensure product launch, Go-To-Market and operational readiness.
- Defining strategic positioning for our EHR to assist other areas of the organization in marketing and positioning of these capabilities.

• Experience in building solid business plans which include appropriate ROI and related business analysis and justification. Demonstrated EHR and/or healthcare information technology expertise within product domain.

April 2014 – March 2015, Hospital Administrator at Diva Healthcare & Eye Institute, Ahmedabad &

October 2012- March 2014, Hospital Administrator at Adarsh Hospital Pvt. Ltd., Valsad, Gujarat

Responsibilities:

- Administering and directing all activities of the hospital and ensures achievement of objectives in providing comprehensive healthcare, training, research, and participation of Community Health, Taking all necessary steps for the maintenance of high standards-professional, technical and supportive.
- To smoothen the functioning of all the departments Clinical (Wards, ICU, Laboratory, Radiology, Emergency etc.) & Non-Clinical (HRD, Medical Record Dept., Maintenance & Engineering Services, Front Office), To develop & refine policies and procedures; To ensure implementation of the same, To establish continuous quality improvement activities leading to improved quality health care services, To ensure the coordination and integration of all quality improvement activities across the departments of the Hospital.
- Delegating duties and responsibilities to appropriate persons in the hospital and preparing periodical reports including the annual report, budgetary proposals, performance reports, and audited statement of accounts.
- Determining the need for staff and has responsibility to select, employ, confirm, grant leave, dismiss and approve salary scales in collaboration with department heads, in accordance with written rules, regulations and outlines of employee duties, Overseeing the acquisition of facilities and purchase of equipment and materials and ensures their proper use.
- Establishing a good system for the careful, economical and proper use of hospital finances, develop adequate financial controls, and prevent misuse of hospital funds and property, ensuring that medical records are properly maintained and safeguarded.

January 2012-August 2012, Healthcare Services Manager at Barchester Healthcare Ltd, Harrow, London (U.K.)

Responsibility: Coordinating and monitoring team activities to simplify integrated proactive care management including Care Access and Monitoring, Case Management, Behavioral Health and Long Term Care. Develops and Assesses team members in the performance of various activities.

- Developing and implements programs to meet the needs of members.
- Performs and promotes interdepartmental integration and collaboration to enhance the continuity of care for members.
- Assessing program performance and participates in the development of enhancement strategies as needed.
- Ensuring adequate staffing and service levels, and maintains customer satisfaction by implementing and monitoring staff productivity and performance indicators.
- Conducting monthly staff meetings
- Participating in selection, orientation and mentoring of new staff members.
- Conducting performance evaluations in a timely manner.

- Providing coaching, counselling and employee development and meets individually with staff at least monthly.
- Assisting team members in improving skills, creativity and problem solving.
- Hands-on manager responsible for oversight and coordination of daily integrated healthcare service activities.
- Achieving and completing assigned work objectives and assignments on a timely basis.
- Contributing to the development of policies and procedures to ensure compliance with regulatory and accrediting standards.
- Creating and ensuring timely and accurate reporting to executive management and appropriate committees.
- Accountable for timely reports submission to regulatory agencies and Plan Partner(s) as required contractually.
- Acting as an information and problem solving resource for team members, physicians, hospitals, and other staff members.
- Working with medical directors regularly, as necessary.
- Facilitates open and well-timed communication
- Knowledge of ICD-9, HCPC and CPT coding.
- Ability to take initiative and see tasks to completion.

September 2010-December 2011, Clinical Coordinator at BUPA Healthcare Ltd, Bushey, London.

Responsibilities:

- Write and create programs and templates to meet user specifications.
- Assist in problem analysis and preparation of programming specifications including flow charts.
- Test and debug programs and templates for accuracy and completeness.
- Prepare technical documentation for each program written.
- Collaborate with Software teams, Clinical Information Analyst, and Clinical information trainers to detect for errors / Defects and ensure resolution.
- Participate in projects and new system implementations.
- Maintain existing systems to meet user requirements.
- Interact with users through various phases of design, implementation, Testing, resolving and maintenance.
- Assist in maintenance of department equipment and supplies including alerting Director of malfunctioning of equipment.
- Assist project management with implementation of tasks for new programs and applications.
- Provide basic training on Clinical Informatics fundamentals for new users of the systems ensuring that all users are informed of and trained on the use of upgrades, new project and application upgrades and training.
- Interface with present and potential internal customers to resolve problems and to maintain high level of customer satisfaction.
- Participate in professional development activities.
- Maintain strictest confidentiality.
- Perform other duties as assigned.

Jan 2010-July 2010, Emergency Medical Officer (E.M.O) and Homoeopathic Physician at Adarsh "Doctor House" Hospital Pvt. Ltd. Valsad, Gujarat, India.

Responsibilities: Supervising administration section of the related wards and taking care of patients with traumatic conditions like accidents, cardiac arrest, injuries, etc.; in Casualty and Emergency wards. Caring during final and emergency stages of life, pre and post-operative care,

creating awareness in the Society regarding various health and safety hazards and regular follow ups of patient at O.P.D and I.P.D level in Hospital and also other duties were as follows:-

- Communicating with patients in order to develop a detailed case history comprising psychological, emotional and physical symptoms and characteristics;
- Using homeopathic remedies to treat a range of conditions e.g. arthritis and eczema;
- Providing medical assistance and treatment consultation, including in-service training, for site
 managers, program coordinators and health care providers within the department and other
 agencies.
- Running seminars and presentations for groups in the community, or for other health practitioners, to promote homeopathy.
- Reviewing, monitoring and preparing schedule for assigned staff to carry out work; problem solving day-to-day operational issues as requested by the senior doctors.
- Assisting in the staff hiring process; providing input to performance evaluations, coaching and on-the job training to staff as requested.

February 2009-December 2009, General Physician (Homoeopathy) at Shri Dharmada Charity Trust Hospital, Vapi, Gujarat, India.

Responsibilities: Checking patients with various health disorders, treating them and doing regular follow ups with homoeopathy treatment at O.P.D. and I.P.D. level of Hospital and handling administrative department.

- Instructing patients about the use and effects of particular remedies;
- advising on lifestyle issues, such as diet, exercise and mental health;
- Referring the patient to other health practitioners, as appropriate;
- Maintaining detailed clinical notes and records for each patient;
- Coordinate designated quality assurance activities and ensures compliance with set standards.
- Perform other duties as assigned.